Charles Johnson

(253) 561-3797 Charles.john87@yahoo.com www.linkedin.com/in/charlesjohnsondeveloper www.github.com/Belvedere-1987 https://belvedere-1987.github.io/

Summary:

Software developer with front end and back end experience programming in C#, Python, JavaScript, SQL, CSS, and HTML. Proven team member with seven years of leadership experience, which included mentoring a team to meet company metrics each quarter. Looking to join a software development team that pushes boundaries and provides regular opportunities for new challenges.

Skills:

Languages: C#, Python, SQL, JavaScript, CSS, HTML

Frameworks/Libraries: Microsoft .Net Framework, Entity Framework, Django, Bootstrap, Knockout

IDEs/Development Tools: Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, SQLite3, Microsoft SQL Server Management Studio,

Agile/Scrum Methodology, Azure DevOps, Adobe Dreamweaver

Other Technical Skills: Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Word, Microsoft Access

Coding Projects

C#/MVC: Built an MVC Car Insurance Application that utilized LINQ and SQLite3 to add customer info to a database. Utilized business logic through methods in the controller to change the customer's quote based on driving record, driver age, car year, and car model. Built an online cart for a produce company utilizing C# and the Knockout JavaScript library.

Python: Created a GUI using the Tkinter interface and OS module to move text files from a source directory to a destination directory on the local hard drive.

SQL: Utilized Microsoft SQL SMS to create a relational database and stored procedures to query information for a library system. Information stored in database included library branch, books available at each branch, book title, book author, and borrower name

Work experience

Software Developer Intern - February 2020 to June 2020 - Proper IT Consulting

C#/MVC: Worked on an MVC website for a local theater company with a team utilizing Agile/Scrum
methodologies and Azure DevOps. Utilized LINQ to seed over 24 items with multiple properties to two
tables in a Entity Framework relational database Additionally worked on fixing styling errors for the website
utilizing razor syntax, CSS, HTML, and Bootstrap 4. Debugged and created multiple links between pages
on the website using URL.Action methods.

Python/Django: Created a CRUD functional application using Python/Django for hobbyists to track
musical equipment by adding, updating, and removing items to a database. The Django application utilized
multiple templates for the user to view information about each item in the database. Applied custom styling
to the application using CSS and HTML..

Contact Center Lead - February 2012 to November 2019 - World Vision

Implemented multiple improvements that dramatically lowered the completion time for multiple contact
center processes. Utilized Microsoft Excel to manage spreadsheets to monitor daily, quarterly, and yearly
statistics for team employees. Coached, monitored, evaluated. and trained contact center team members
to meet and exceed expectation in donor experience quality, call handle times, and successful sale
percentages monthly, quarterly, and yearly.

Interim Donor Contact Center Trainer - September 2011 to December 2011 - World Vision

Trained two twelve person classes in a four week 40 hours a week classroom environment to make and
take customer service phone calls as well as operate World Vision's CRM database during the highest call
volume quarter of the year for World Vision's contact center. Created through Adobe Dreamweaver an
interactive e-learning tool that simulated a typical customer service phone call that incorporated audio
manipulated through the Audacity audio editing program.

Technical Education

Tech Academy Full Stack Developer Certification- November 2019 - June 2020

• The Tech Academy's Full Stack Developer course is an intensive coding program that takes over 4000 hours of study to complete. It teaches its students how to code through practical drills and online videos on HTML, CSS, C#, SQL, and Python languages. The course starts with the fundamentals of each programming language and builds up to complex coding concepts through hands on programming. An emphasis is also placed on learning the tools and methodologies utilized by coding professionals such as Agile/Scrum, Visual Studio, Github and clean version control.

Academic Education

Bachelor of Arts - English Major/Speech Communication Minor East Texas Baptist University - Marshall, TX 2008

 Interpersonal Communication and Listening classes taken during the B.A. degree that emphasized the importance of empathy, active listening, and how to communicate effectively with varied perspectives, personalities, and work behaviours.

Associate in Arts - Green River Community College - Auburn, WA 2005